ha the
公顷
the norm
规范
are
有
last time
上次
we began the discussion I'll discrete-time processing
我们开始讨论我将离散时间处理
love continuous-time signals and
爱连续时间信号和
as a reminder let me review
作为一个提醒，让我回顾
the basic notion the idea was
基本概念的想法是
dead we convert
死了我们转换
from a continuous-time signal to a sequence
从连续时间信号的序列
through an operation which I
通过操作，我
represent as a continuous to discrete-time converter
代表作为连续到离散时间转换器
and then that sequence
然后该序列
is used as the input to
被用作输入到
inappropriate discrete-time system
不恰当的离散时间系统
and after appropriate discrete-time processing
并经过适当的离散时间处理
that sequence is converted
该序列被转换
back to a continuous-time signal
返回到连续时间信号
through an operation which i-label as
通过操作该I-标签为
a discrete to continuous-time converter
一个离散的连续时间转换器
now in the lecture
如今在讲座
last time we carried out some analysis
我们进行了一些分析，最后一次
which related 4s the spectra
其中4S光谱相关
in the first step this operation namely
在第一步骤中这个操作即
in the transformation from a continuous-time
在从连续时间转换
signal to sequence and
对信号序列和
let me by the way draw your attention to the fact
让我的方式提请你注意一个事实，
that in the real world this operation
在现实世界中该操作
is essentially implemented
基本上实现
by what you would typically label as an analog to digital converter
由你通常会标示为模拟到数字转换器
if in fact the discrete-time processing
如果实际上离散时间处理
is being done digitally now it's important to emphasize that it's not
正在做数字现在强调的是，它不是很重要
exactly what an analog to digital converter
正是模拟 - 数字转换器
does but in some sense at least you should think
确实，但在某种意义上，至少你应该考虑
love this mapping from continuous time to discrete-time
喜欢这个映射从连续时间到离散时间
in very much the same way there one would think an analog to digital
在非常有相同的方式人们会认为一个模拟到数字
converter
变流器
and the mapping back and is corresponds
和映射回，且对应
in some sense to a what would happen
在某种意义上，一个会发生什么
with a digital to analog converter well
与数字到模拟转换器以及
let me review what is involved in the mapping from
让我回顾一下涉及的映射关系
the continuous-time signal to the sequence and
连续时间信号的序列和
let me stress again that this operation
让我再次强调，此操作
is basically in the continues to discrete-time conversion
基本上是在继续离散时间转换
a two-step process in
在一个两步骤的过程
the first part of the process the continuous-time signal
该过程的第一部分的连续时间信号
is modulated with an impulse train
调制与脉冲串
where the period of the imposed strain is capital T
其中所施加的应变的周期为大写字母T
and so we have a continuous-time
所以我们有一个连续时间
impose Train Signal which captures
并处火车信号捕获
the samples love the original continuous-time signals
样品爱情原来的连续时间信号
that in Paul strain
在保罗应变
is then put through an operation
然后，通过操作放
which essentially re labels
这基本上重新标签
the samples so that the
样品，使
sample values the impulse areas
采样值的冲动领域
are relabeled as sequence values
被重新标记为序列值
and the result of that conversion is then
而转换的结果是再
the sequence X event so the overall process then
该序列X事件，因此整个过程，然后
is a sampling process followed by
在一个取样过程随后
what is simply in this box relabeling
什么是简单地在此框中重新标记
process and although as I
过程虽然我
indicated just a minute ago that is essentially what an analog to digital
表示只有一分钟以前，基本上是什么模拟到数字
converter does
不转换
now like to digital converter doesn't necessarily carry it out
现在像数字转换器不一定抓落实
in those two steps but particularly
在这两个步骤，但特别
in terms love carrying through an analysis
在爱情方面，通过实施分析
thinking of it as a two-step process is particularly convenient
想到它作为一个两步骤的过程是特别方便
now we talked last time
现在我们谈最后一次
about what this mapping from continuous time to discrete-time
什么这个映射从连续时间到离散时间
means both in the time domain in terms of the spectra
装置，无论是在在光谱方面的时域
and in particular in the time domain we
特别是在时域中我们
begin with the continuous-time signal
开始的连续时间信号
which is then samples with an impulse train
然后将其与一个脉冲串样本
and converted to a sequence by
并转换为一个序列由
simply generating a sequence whose values
简单地生成一个序列，其值
are the area is love the impulses
正在该地区是爱的冲动
and I stress the fact that what this corresponds to
我必须强调这是什么此相对应的事实
essentially is and normalization of the time axis
基本上是和时间轴的归一化
essentially by dividing the time axis by capital T
基本上是由时间轴由大写字母T除以
in the frequency-domain then
在频域，然后
we had the spectrum of the original signal
我们有原始信号的频谱
which because that the sampling process is
这是因为，采样过程是
replicated at multiples integer multiples
在倍数的整数倍复制
all the sampling frequency Omega so badass
所有的采样频率欧米茄所以坏蛋
or to pile over capital T
或堆放在大写字母T
and then in converting the impulses
然后，在变换所述脉冲
to a sequence we are essentially
一个序列，我们基本上是
normalizing the frequency axis so that
频率轴上的归一化，使得
the frequency to pile over capital T gets relabeled is to pie
频率堆放在大写字母T被重新标记是馅饼
and the resulting discrete-time spectrum looks like
将得到的离散时间频谱看起来像
I indicate here which really is
我在这里指出哪个是真的
nothing more and a frequency scaling
仅此而已和频率缩放
corresponding to the Associated time scaling so the mapping
对应于所述相关联的时间缩放这样的映射
from the imposed strain spectrum to the discrete-time spectrum
由所施加的应变的频谱的离散时间谱
corresponds to mapping specified
对应于指定的映射
by capital Omega equal to small make a times capital T
通过资本欧米茄等于小赚了次大写字母T
an equivalent Lee it's the frequency
等效利它的频率
to pile over capital T which is
堆放在大写字母T是
of course the sampling frequency which gets normalized
当然采样频率，得到归一化
to the frequency to pie
到的频率来馅饼
and so in the frequency domain
因此在频域
their is a frequency normalization Associated
它们是相关联的频率归一化
with the fact dead corresponding to this spectrum
与事实死对应于该谱
is a time sequence or discrete time sequence
是一个时间序列或离散时间序列
as I show previously and a discrete-time sequence
如我先前和离散时间序列
is related to the
是关系到
original continuous-time signal
原来的连续时间信号
through a time normalization in other words
通过时间正常化，换句话说
these sequence values are simply samples at the continuous-time signal
这些序列值进行简单的样品在连续时间信号
with the time axis we normalized
与我们归一化的时间轴
now what we want to consider this is the conversion from continuous time to
现在我们要考虑这个东西是从连续时间转换
discrete-time
离散时间
what we want to consider now is the overall system
我们现在要考虑的是整个系统的
which implements not just the conversion but filtering
它实现了不只是转换，但过滤
and then coming back onto the conversion back to continuous-time
然后回来到转换回连续时间
so let's look at the overall system
所以让我们来看看整个系统
and the overall system courses I've
和整个系统的课程我已经
stressed several times in the past consists
过去由强调过好几次
love first the sampling process
第一次爱的采样过程
conversion to an impulse train
转换到一个脉冲串
and the imposed strain converted to a sequence
和所施加的应变转换为一个序列
that sequence is then processed
然后该序列被处理
through are discrete-time filter
通过为离散时间滤波器
and after the discrete-time processing
和离散时间处理后
the result of that is converted back
的，该结果被转换回
to an impulse train so this resulting process sequence
一个脉冲串所以这个过程产生的序列
is then converted back to an impulse train
然后转换回一个脉冲串
and then finally we carry out the the sampling
然后最后我们进行的抽样
process by simply using a low-pass filter
过程通过简单地使用一个低通滤波器
Associated with the with the cutoff associated with the sampling frequency
相关联的带的采样频率有关的截止
that we use
我们使用
now typically in a system like that which implements
现在通常在这样的系统，它实现
discrete-time processing continuous-time signals
离散时间处理连续时间信号
we either we need to ensure in one way or another
我们或者我们需要确保在这样或那样的
that the band with love the input is
与爱乐队的输入是
sufficiently limited so that we avoid aliasing
足够的限制，使我们避免混淆
one way to do that is to force it in one way or another or
要做到这一点的方法之一是迫使它以某种方式或
simply know that our signal satisfies the band with constrain
只是知道，我们的信号满足乐队与约束
although a fairly typical thing to do in addition
虽然一个相当典型的事情，除了
to this sampling process is
该采样过程是
to include what is referred to as
为包括被称为
and anti aliasing filter in other words this is a filter
和换句话说抗混叠滤波器，这是一个过滤器
that would ban limit the input
，将禁止限制输入
and at least half the sampling frequency
和至少一半的采样频率
so that we r guaranteed and
让我们r保证，
that their is no aliasing it's carried out
他们是没有走样它进行
in this process and it's important
在这一过程中，重要的
to stress dead in this kinda processing discrete-time processing
强调死在这有点儿处理离散时间处理
continuous-time signals except in certain
除了在某些连续时间信号
special situations its very important
特殊情况下它很重要
to avoid aliasing because we're going to want
为了避免混淆，因为我们要去想
to do a reconstruction after we do the sampling and processing
做一个改造后，我们做了采样和处理
okay now this is the sequence of steps in the time domain
还好现在这个步骤在时域序列
let's examine what happens as a consequence is this
让我们来看看会发生什么的结果是这样
in the frequency domain well
在频域以及
let's choose some typeof simple representative spectrum
让我们来选择一些简单的typeof代表频谱
and of course what's important about it is that
当然，什么是它重要的是，
the specter that we choose is banned limited or that there's an anti-aliasing
我们选择的幽灵被禁止或限制该有一个抗混叠
filter
过滤器
and it's not the shape of course that is critical
它不是当然的形状是很关键
and as we work our way through the system
当我们通过该系统工作的方式
this is the continuous-time spectrum
这是连续时间频谱
after sampling that spectrum is replicated at
采样后的频谱被复制在
multiples of the sampling frequency integer multiples the sampling frequency
的采样频率的整数倍的倍数的采样频率
and so
等
there would be another one over here and another one over here at cetera
会有另外一个在这里，另一个在这里等等
and then in converting to a discrete-time sequence
然后在变换为离散时间序列
their is The Associated
它们是相关联的
frequency normalization so that the sampling frequency
频率归一化，使采样频率
yes normalized to a frequency
是归一化到一个频率
to pie okay now at that point
到馅饼还好现在在这一点上
where we are in the system
我们在系统中
is at this point
在这一点
so that we've converted to a sequence we now
所以，我们现在已经转化为一个序列，我们
want to carry out some filtering and then after that filtering
要进行一些过滤，然后在过滤后
convert back to a continuous-time signals
转换回一个连续时间信号
alright so here we are at the
好吧所以这里我们都在
spectrum Associated with the
频谱相关的
sequence and now
序列和现在
the processing they were carrying out is
他们进行的处理是
linear time-invariant filtering in the discrete time domain
在离散时间域线性时不变滤波
and what that corresponds to then is multiplying
什么对应然后乘以
this spectrum by the filter frequency response and I've chosen
这个频谱的滤波器的频率响应和我选择
a particular shape and again it's not the shape that's important to the
特定的形状，并再次它不是形状是很重要的
discussion
讨论
but the fact for example that it has a particular cutoff frequency which will
但事实上，例如，它有一个特定的截止频率的，这将
kinda track
还挺追踪
as we work through this and so now
当我们通过这个工作，所以现在
the spectrum of why I have an the output
为什么我有一个输出频谱
the digital filter is the product this spectrum
数字滤波器是产品这个频谱
and the 4e a transformer frequency response
而4E变压器的频率响应
I'll the digital filter
我将数字滤波器
now in working our way through we're going to take the output at the filter
现在我们的工作方式，通过我们将采取输出滤波器
and undo the two-step process so we now want to take that sequence
并撤消了两步过程，所以我们现在要采取的序列
converted to an impulse train and then take then imposed strain
转换到一个脉冲串，然后再采取应变征收
Andy sample through a low-pass filter
通过一个低通滤波器，安迪样品
so here we are now at the output to the digital filter
所以在这里，我们现在是在输出到数字滤波器
we then convert that to an impulse train well that's really on doing the original
我们再转换到一个脉冲串清楚，真的做好原
time normalization
时间正常化
and so what that means is that we
所以这是什么意思是，我们
are on doing the frequency normalization in particular
都在做，特别是归一化频率
we're dividing the frequency axis by
我们将频率轴由
capital T whereas this point
大写字母T，而这一点
in y Omega was to pie
沿y欧米茄是馅饼
now it's to pile over capital T
现在是堆放在大写字母T
what that means is that acquittal and Lee were multiplying this spectrum
这是什么意思是，无罪释放和李本均乘以谱
by the frequency response the digital filter
由频率响应的数字滤波器
but now linearly scaled in frequency
但现在线性缩放的频率
so that will what was a cutoff frequency Omega subsea
因此，这将是怎样的截止频率欧米茄海底
is now a cutoff frequency up Omega subsea
现在是一个截止频率高达欧米茄海底
divided by capital T so
由大写字母T划分，从而
now the next step in the process is the reconstructing
现在在这个过程中，下一步是将重构
low-pass filter and what that extracts is simply the portion
低通滤波器和什么提取仅仅是部分
I'll this periodic spectrum around the origin
我将围绕原点这个周期性频谱
and so finally and spectrum of the output
等终于和输出频谱
up the overall system will be the spectrum
了整个系统将是频谱
of the input multiplied
输入的相乘
by a frequency response
由一个频率响应
which is the digital filter frequency response
这是数字滤波器的频率响应
frequency scaled by dividing
频率缩放除以
that digital filter frequency axis by capital T
由大写字母T的数字滤波器频率轴
okay now what we can ask is
还好现在我们可以问的是
we've got this processing we've converted to discrete-time we've gone
我们已经得到了这个处理我们已经转换为离散时间，我们已经走了
back to continuous-time
回连续时间
and one can ask now what acquittal and
和一个现在可以问什么无罪释放及
overall continuous-time systems is that correspond to
整体连续时间系统是对应于
in other words if we that of course is a continuous-time system it's a continuous
换句话说，如果我们认为当然是一个连续时间系统是一个连续的
time you put a continuous-time output
时间你把一个连续时间输出
and the overall system dan
和整个系统的担
would be one that would give us exactly the same output spectrum
将是一个会给我们完全一样的输出频谱
as we're getting well what is that well we have
因为我们越来越清楚什么是好，我们有
is an output spectrum which is the product
是输出光谱是该产品
all the input spectrum and digital filter frequency characteristic
所有的输入频谱和数字滤波器的频率特性
frequency scale and so in fact
频率刻度等实际上
the resulting digital filter I'm sorry continuous-time
由此产生的数字滤波器对不起连续时间
filter is simply the digital filter
过滤器是简单的数字滤波器
with inappropriate frequency scaling
用不恰当的频率缩放
in other words with the frequency axis divided by capital T
换句话说，与频率轴由大写字母T划分
so sent another way if
所以派出的另一种方式，如果
we show here
我们在这里展示
the frequency response or the
的频率响应或
original digital filter
原来的数字滤波器
then the corresponding continuous-time
然后相应的连续时间
filter would be this
过滤器会是这样
frequency scaled and then because love
频率缩放，然后因为爱情
The Associated low-pass filtering in the reconstruction
在重建相关的低通滤波
we would select out just one of these periods in particular the portion around
我们将选择这些时段特别是只有一个周围的部分
the origin
原产地
and the essential consequences that is that the corresponding
和必要的后果是，对应
continuous-time filter then is
连续时间滤波器则是
given by this and these two are related
通过此给出，与这两个是相关的
simply by a linear scaling the frequency axis
简单地通过线性标度的频率轴
and note dead where the digital filter has a cutoff frequency
和记死其中数字滤波器具有一个截止频率
Omega subsea the continuous-time filter
欧米加海底的连续时间滤波器
has a cutoff frequency Omega subsea divided by capital T
有一个截止频率欧米茄海底除以大写字母T
so that's the linear frequency scaling and
所以这是线性频率调节和
by the way plant away for now and will return to this point later
顺便说一句植物离开现在，稍后会回到这个点
plant the way for now the the observation
对于现在的观察种植方式
dad even if the digital filter frequency response
爸即使数字滤波器的频率响应
is fixed which we would assume it is
是固定的，我们就假设它是
by changing the sampling frequency in fact
通过改变实际上采样频率
what we're able to do is a fact a linear scaling
什么，我们能够做的是一个事实，一个线性缩放
or the acquittal in continuous-time
或者在连续时间的无罪判决
okay well this is pretty much the process in the analysis
还好还有这是相当多的过程分析
but to highlight a number the issues and emphasize these points
但是，突出了一些问题，并强调这几点
why I like to do is illustrate
为什么我喜欢做的是说明
somewhat this with a videotape demonstration
这有点用录像带演示
that in fact was made originally as part of another course a course
这实际上是做最初作为另一个进程的一部分课程
devoted entirely to
完全致力于
digital signal processing which essentially is discrete-time processing
这基本上是离散时间处理的数字信号处理
whether or not it's related to continuous-time signals
不论它涉及到连续时间信号
and what I'd like to now focus on
什么，我想现在专注于
are summer the details of that demonstration
是夏天演示的细节
in the demonstration the
在示范
specific impulse response there
有特定的脉冲响应
is used for the digital filter
用于数字滤波器
or discrete-time filter is the one that I show here
或离散时间滤波器是，我在这里展示一
and the Associated
和美联社
frequency response is the frequency response
频率响应是频率响应
love a discrete-time low-pass filter as i indicate below
爱一个离散时间低通滤波器，因为我在下面注明
and the cutoff frequency that filter as i indicate the filter was designed as a
和截止频率的滤波器为我指明了过滤器被设计成一个
discreet I felt with the cutoff frequency hi over five
谨慎的，我觉得与截止频率喜超五类
and let me just draw your attention to the fact that
并让我提请您注意的是，
pie over five is also
馅饼五年也
10 love to pie
10爱馅饼
and so in fact the digital
所以实际上数字
for discrete-time filter cutoff frequency is a tenth
对于离散时间滤波器的截止频率是第十
to pie and as all stress again shortly
以饼和所有的压力在短期内再次
remember that in the frequency normalization
记得在归一化频率
or a normalization to pie represents
或正常化派代表
in effect the sampling frequency and so
实际上，采样频率等
the consequence of that is that cutoff frequency really is going to be
那后果是，截止频率确实将是
associated
相关
with the 10th all the sampling frequency but for now keep in mind that is just
与10日所有的采样频率，但现在要记住，这只是
simply attentive to
只是细心的
on now the
在现在
equivalent continuous-time
等效连续时间
system interns are the impulse response
系统实习生的脉冲响应
is of course a ban limited interpolation
当然是禁止插值有限
love the up the
爱了
impose response associated with the discrete-time
响应施加的离散时间相关联
filter and in the frequency domain the frequency response
过滤并在频域中的频率响应
is correspondingly a timescale
是相应的时间尺度
and a timescale I'm sorry a frequency scale
和时间表对不起频率规模
version at the frequency response so in fact
版本的频率响应，从而在事实上
in the frequency domain and in the time domain
在频域和时域中的
related to the continuous-time signal
相关的连续时间信号
the Associated impulse response is
美联社脉冲响应
what I indicate here a ban limited interpolation
我在这里表示禁止插值有限
or the discrete-time impulse response
或离散时间冲激响应
and time scale than
比时间尺度
and the frequency response following the discussion that we've previously gone
和频率响应下面我们先前已经走了讨论
through
通过
is a frequency scale version all the one associated with the digital filter
是一个频率刻度版本的所有一个具有数字滤波器相关
well the first thing that all want to look at is
以及所有想要看的第一件事就是
the impulse response and when we do
脉冲响应，当我们做
let me just indicate that
让我表明，
in the actual implementation things are slightly different
在实际执行的事情略有不同
then they are associated with the ideal analysis
然后将它们与理想的分析相关联的
in particular in converting
特别是在转换
from a discrete-time sequence
从离散时间序列
to the continuous-time signal whereas
到而连续时间信号
this way of looking at it is convenient
这样看着很方便
in the context that the analysis in fact the way it's done
在该分析中的事实的方式，它的完成的情况下
is is using more or less
是采用更多或更少
standard digital to analog converter
标准的数字到模拟转换器
one what a digital to analog converter does as i indicated in the previous
1什么是数字到模拟转换器确实正如我在以前的
lecture
演讲
is to convert the sequence
是要转换的序列
not to an impulse train but in fact to go directly through
不是一个冲动的火车，但其实直接通过去
zero-order hold and so usually what comes onto
零阶保持，所以通常随之而来的上
a digital to analog converter is a staircase
一个数字到模拟转换器是一个楼梯
tightness signal associated with the zero-order hold
与零阶保持气密性相关的信号
and then the result of that is low-pass filter to do the reconstruction
然后的，结果是低通滤波器，以执行重建
so what we want to look at and is
所以我们想看看，什么是
that reconstruction first with just an impulse input
该重建第一只用一个脉冲输入
and so what we'll see after the low-pass filter
还等什么，我们的低通滤波器后，会看到
for the impulse response is
供的脉冲响应是
a smooth curve like this but also as part of the demonstration
平滑的曲线像​​这样同时也作为示范的一部分
what all do just to show the zero-order hold
什么都做，是想说明的零阶保持
is to take the low-pass filter out temporarily
是采取低通滤波器输出暂时
and then put it back in so first let's just look at
然后将其放回，所以首先让我们来只是看看
the filter impulse response
该滤波器的脉冲响应
what we see here is the impost response
我们在这里看到的是什么关税响应
all the overall system and
所有整体系统和
we observe for one thing that it's a symmetrical impulse response in other
我们观察到一件事，它是在其他对称的脉冲响应
words corresponds to a linear phase filter
字对应于一个线性相位滤波器
we can also look at the impulse response before that the same playing
我们还可以看看脉冲响应之前，同样的播放
low-pass filter let's take out that the sampling low-pass filter
低通滤波器，让我们拿出了采样低通滤波器
slowly and wide
慢慢地，宽
we observe is basically the output I'll
我们观察基本上是输出我会
the digital to analog converter which of course is a staircase a boxcar function
数字到模拟转换器，当然这是一个楼梯一个棚车功能
not an impulse train in the real world the
在现实世界中不一个脉冲串的
output over the day converted generally is a boxcar type function
输出过的日子通常是转换成一个功能型棚车
we can put the the sampling filter back in now
我们可以把采样滤波器早在现在
and notice that the effectivity sampling filter is basically
并注意有效性采样滤波器基本上
to smooth out the rough edges in
理顺在粗糙的边缘
the boxcar output from the DA converter
从DA转换器输出的矩形波串
okay so that's the impulse response the system
好了，这就是脉冲响应系统
now what I like to show is the frequency
现在我想展示的是频率
response the system and to measure the frequency response of course what we can
响应的系统和测量过程的频率响应我们所能
do
is put a sine wave
是把一个正弦波
into the system and looked at
进入系统，看着
the sinusoidal output so in particular now what will happen is that
正弦输出，所以尤其现在会发生什么事是，
with the system we will put in
与系统我们将投入
a continuous-time sinusoid which is sampled
一个被采样的连续时间正弦曲线
converted to a sequence
转换成一个序列
the sample continues sigh sinus so it is a discrete-time sinusoid
样品继续叹息窦所以它是一个离散时间正弦曲线
that goes through the digital filter and gets attenuated or
该经过数字滤波和被衰减或
amplified appropriately and then
适当地再扩增
the output if that is converted back and that's
输出如果被转换回，这就是
again a sinusoidal output that gets converted back
再一个正弦输出，被转换回
to a continuous-time sinusoid
到连续时间正弦曲线
theoretically as i indicate here but again as we just saw
理论上，因为我在此表明却又像我们刚才看到的
really represented by zero-order hold followed by
真正的零阶保持后跟代表
a low-pass filter so thats
一个低通滤波器，因此多数民众赞成
the overall operation with one
与1的整体操作
modification from the diagram that we have here
修改从我们这里有图
in this particular diagram I've included
在这个特殊的图我已经包括
a and anti-aliasing filter
一和抗混叠滤波器
in fact in the demonstration there is no
实际上在示范没有
anti-aliasing filter and so
抗混叠滤波器等
in fact the input is a sinusoidal input
实际上输入的是正弦输入
which is not band limited
这不是带宽限制
by virtue of an anti-aliasing filter it's only
凭借一个抗混叠滤波器，这只是
course been limited appropriately
当然了适当的限制
if we choose the sinusoidal frequency that way
如果我们选择的正弦频率的方法
so there is no anti-aliasing filter and this is the system
所以没有抗混叠滤波器，这是该系统
and one consequence if that
和一个后果，如果该
is dead in fact if we sweep
死了，其实，如果我们扫
the input sinusoid only up to half the sampling frequency
在输入正弦信号只到采样频率的一半
will see no aliasing but if we let its we passed that we're going to get
会看到没有走样，但如果我们让了我们通过，我们会得到
aliasing
走样
now in the demonstration the sampling rate
现在在示范采样率
its picked for this party the demonstration is a 20 kilohertz sampling
其钦点为这个党的演示是一个20千赫的采样
rate
率
that means based on the sampling theorem that as long as the input frequency
这意味着根据抽样定理，只要将输入频率
is below 10 killer hurts we get no aliasing
低于10的杀手伤害我们得到没有走样
when the input frequency goes beyond 10 killer hurts
当输入频率超出10杀手伤害
that higher frequency is going to get alias down
较高的频率是会得到别名下来
into a lower frequency a consequence is that then
成较低频率的结果是，然后
is that as we go through the process saying
就是因为我们经历的过程说
and we demonstrate the frequency response to the system
我们证明了频率响应的系统
what we'll see in the output is
我们在输出会看到
no alias saying when the input is below 10 killer hurts
没有别名说，当输入低于10杀手伤害
as the input sweeps past 10 killer hurts
作为输入扫过10杀手伤害
when when we let it which we will eventually in the demonstration
时，当我们让它是我们最终将在示范
dan in fact that frequency as it finally shows up here
丹其实这个频率，因为它终于在这里显示
will begin to be aliased down into a lower frequency
将开始向下混叠到一个较低的频率
another way thinking about that is dead
另一种方式思考即死
when we watch the frequency response
当我们观看的频率响应
love the system as
爱系统
we look at the digital filter frequency response
我们来看一下数字滤波器的频率响应
what we're sweeping and as we go from zero
我们正在扫地，当我们从零
up to 10 killer hurts
高达10杀手伤害
in the input frequency is this portion of the frequency response
在输入频率为频率响应的该部分
as we sweep from 10 killer hurts out to 20 kilohertz
我们从10杀手横扫伤害到20千赫
what we'll see is this portion the frequency response
我们将看到的是这部分的频率响应
in other words will see it periodically replicate
换句话说，会看到它周期性地复制
or if we look at the
或者，如果我们看一下
corresponding continuous-time frequency response
相应的连续时间的频率响应
what it means really is that sweeping
这是什么意思真的就是这么笼统
from 0 to 10 killer hurts
从0到10的杀手伤害
is moving up this way and then sweeping from 10 killer hurts
是动起来这种方式，然后从10杀手席卷疼
to 20 kilohertz on the input
至20千赫的输入
really because if the alias saying
真的是因为如果说别名
reflects itself in a digital filter by
反映到由一个数字滤波器
looking back down it toward lower frequencies and so the continuous-time
回头向下移向更低的频率，因此在连续时间
filter
过滤器
sweeps back down from 10 killer hurts
从扫10杀手回落疼
back 20 okay
回20好
so that so we'll see and we'll see it in several different ways as explained in
让所以我们会看到，我们会看到它在几个不同的方式解释中
the demonstration
示范
so now let's look and the frequency response
所以现在让我们来看看和频率响应
sold now we like to illustrate
现在卖我们喜欢来说明
is the frequency response love the acquittal in continuous-time
在频率响应爱的连续时间无罪
filter and we can do that by sweeping the filter with a sinusoidal input
过滤，我们可以做到这一点的清扫过滤器，正弦输入
so what we'll see in this demonstration is
所以我们会在这个演示中看到的是
on the upper trace the input sinusoid on the lower trace the output sinusoid
在上部迹线在下部的输入正弦跟踪输出正弦
using a 20 kilohertz sampling rate in a sweep
使用20千赫兹的采样率在一个扫描
from 0 to 10 killer hurts in other words a sweep from 0 to
从0到10的杀手伤害换句话说从0扫描至
effectively hi interns at the digital filter
有效喜实习生在数字滤波器
so work will observe as the input frequency increases
这样的工作将遵守作为输入频率的增加
is that the output sinusoid will have essentially constant amplitude
是，输出正弦曲线将具有基本上恒定的幅度
up to the cutoff frequency the filter and then approximately zero amplitude
到截止频率的滤波器，然后约零振幅
past so let's now sweet the filter
过去，所以现在让我们甜蜜的过滤器
frequency response
频率响应
and the area is the filter
和面积的过滤器
cutoff frequency
截止频率
now we can also observe the filter frequency response in
现在我们也可以观察滤波器的频率响应
several other ways one way in which we can observe it is by
在此我们可以观察到它的几个其他的方法一种方法是通过
looking also at the amplitude if the output sinusoid as
也期待在幅度如果输出为正弦波
a function of frequency rather than as a function of time
频率的函数，而不是作为时间的函数
and so will observe that on the left-hand SCO
因此将观察到，在左手SCO
while on the right-hand scope will have the same trace their we just saw
而在右边的范围将具有相同的跟踪他们，我们只是看到了
namely to traces the upper traces the input sinusoid
即轨迹上的痕迹的输入正弦
the lower traces the output sinusoid and in addition to observing
较低的痕迹输出正弦曲线和除观察
the frequency response let's also listen to the output sinusoid
频率响应，让我们也听的输出正弦波
and observe the attenuation
并观察衰减
in the output as we go from the field to pass band to the filter stopping again a
在输出，因为我们去从外地来通带至过滤器再次停​​止
20 kilohertz sampling rate
20千赫的采样率
and a sweep range from 0 to 10 killer now
和扫描范围从0到10的杀手现在
course when the filter stop
当然，当过滤器停止
now if we increase the sweep range
现在，如果我们增加扫描范围
from 10 killer hurts the 20 kilohertz
从10杀手伤害了20千赫
so that the sweep range is equal to the sampling frequency
使扫描范围等于采样频率
in essence that corresponds the sweeping at the digital filter
在对应扫在数字滤波器本质
from 0 to 2pi and in that case we'll begin to see
从0到2PI，并在这种情况下，我们将开始看到
some %uh the periodicity in the digital filter frequency response
一些％呃在数字滤波器的频率响应的周期性
so let's do that now with 20 kilohertz sampling rate
所以让我们现在要做的，与20千赫的采样率
and a sweep range is 0 to 20 kilohertz
和一个扫描范围是0到20千赫
now as we come near to Pine
现在，当我们走近松
we get back into the past
我们重新回到过去
an finally back to
最后一回
a0 to 10 killer hurts we so they were again sweeping
a0到10杀手伤害我们，使他们再次席卷
only from 0 to 2pi with regard to the digital filter
只有从0到2PI对于数字滤波器
now an important observation is that
现在是一个重要的发现是，
with the digital or discrete-time
与数字或离散时间
filter cutoff frequency fixed as i've indicated here
滤波器的截止频率固定的，因为我已经在这里表示
and I remind you that what the cutoff frequency is
我提醒你，什么样的截止频率为
is a 10 to hi with that cutoff frequency fixed
是一个10来喜与截止频率固定
because I love the normalization that we get
因为我爱，我们得到正常化
as we come back to a continuous-time
当我们回过头来连续时间
filter in fact what we have
其实我们所拥有的筛选
is a cutoff frequency dead is
是一个截止频率为死
dependent on the sampling frequency or on the sampling period
依赖于采样频率或采样周期
and more specifically since the discrete-time or digital
更具体地，因为离散时间或数字
filter has a cutoff frequency which is attentive to pie
滤波器的截止频率是细心的馅饼
the normalization as you recall
你还记得正常化
is dead to pie in discrete-time frequency
是死馅饼离散时间频率
corresponds to Omega sed s/ the sampling frequency
对应于欧米茄SED秒/采样频率
in terms of continuous-time frequency the consequence
在连续时间频率方面的后果
is dead this cutoff frequency in fact
其实这死的截止频率
is 110 all
110是所有
not to pine now because at the normalization its 110
现在不以松，因为在它的正常化110
I'll the sampling frequency so
我将采样频率使
consequently as we change the sampling frequency
因此，我们改变采样频率
what will happen is that even with the discrete-time filter cutoff fixed
会发生什么事是，即使与离散时间滤波器的截止固定
the cutoff frequency I'll the equivalent continuous-time
截止频率，我将相当于连续时间
filter will change now
过滤器将改变现在
that's what I want to demonstrate but let me
这就是我要证明，但让我
again stress and ask you to keep in mind dead
再次强调并要求你记住死
this demonstration is done without an anti-aliasing filter in
这次示威是在没有一个抗混叠滤波器进行
and we are going to be changing the sampling frequency
而我们将要改变采样频率
and so keep in mind dead as
所以请记住死的，因为
we look at this as the input frequency
我们来看看本作的输入频率
sweeps past half the sampling frequency whatever sampling frequency we happen to
扫过采样频率的一半无论采样频率，我们碰巧
be looking at
在看
then because the fact that there's no anti-aliasing filter
然后，因为事实上，没有抗混叠滤波器
will get daily as saying in other words the frequency in the digital filter
每天将获得的话说，换句话说频率的数字滤波器
discrete-time filter as we sweep the input frequency up
离散时间滤波器为我们扫输入频率高达
will move up in frequency until we get
将在频率上移，直到我们得到
past half the sampling frequency and then essentially will move back down
过去采样频率的一半，然后基本上将移动回落
frequency consequently what will get
频率因此什么会
then are or we'll see our periodic replications
再有，否则我们将看到我们定期复制
the frequency response when we swept past have see half the sampling alright
频率响应，当我们横扫过去曾看到一半的采样好吗
so now
所以现在
let's look at the same digital filter
让我们来看看同样的数字滤波器
but the frequency response as
但是，频率响应为
we change the sampling frequency now
我们现在改变采样频率
what we would like to demonstrate is the effective changing the same thing
我们想证明是有效的改变同样的事情
frequency and we know that
频率和我们知道，
the sampling that the effective filter cutoff frequency
采样的有效滤波器的截止频率
is tied to the sampling frequency
是依赖于采样频率
and for this particular filter corresponds to attend
并为这个特殊的过滤器对应出席
of the sampling frequency consequently if we double the sampling frequency we
采样频率因而，如果我们的两倍的采样频率我们
should double
应该加倍
the affective filter past and where war
情感过滤过去，那里的战争
double the filter cutoff frequency and
加倍滤波器的截止频率和
so let's do that now it again is 0-10 killer hurt sweep range
所以让我们做，现在它再次为0-10杀手伤扫描范围
but a forty kilohertz sampling frequency
但一个40千赫的采样频率
me and
我和
we should observe that the filter cutoff frequency has now doubled
我们应该看到，滤波器的截止频率已经翻了一翻
out 24 killer now
出24现在杀手
let's begin to decrease the filter sampling frequency
让我们开始降低滤波器的采样频率
so from forty let's change the sampling frequency to 20 kilohertz
所以从40让我们的采样频率改为20赫兹
we should see the cutoff frequency cut in half me
我们应该看到的截止频率降低一半我
now we can go even further we can cut the sampling frequency down
现在我们可以再进一步，我们可以减少采样频率下降
10 killer hurts and remember that the sweep range is 0 to 10 killer hurt so
10杀手伤害，记住，扫描范围为0〜10的杀手伤得这么
now will be sweeping from 0 to 2pi
现在从0扫到2PI
so as we get close to two pi will see the passband again
所以随着我们接近两圆周率将再次看到通带
and now
现在
let's cut down the sampling frequency even further
让我们砍下采样频率进一步
to by kilohertz my
由千赫我
here we are at 2pi
在这里，我们是在二皮音乐
and then
进而
at for pop alright so
在对流行这么好吗
that illustrates the effective changing the sampling frequency
示出改变采样频率的有效
now let's conclude this demonstration at the effect
现在让我们来总结这次示范的作用
on the sampling frequency on the filter cutoff frequency by carrying out some
对滤波器的截止频率的采样频率通过进行一些
filtering
过滤
on some live audio white will
一些现场音频白色的意志
watching this case is the output
看着这种情况下是输出
audio waveform as a function of time
音频波形作为时间的函数
on the single trace go and also
在单一的跟踪去也
will listen to the output will begin it with a forty killer hurts
会听的输出将开始它与40杀手伤害
sampling rate then reduce that to 20 kilohertz 10 killer hurts and then five
采样率则减少至20千赫兹10杀手伤害再五
alerts
警报
and in each of those cases the effective filter cutoff frequency
并在每个这些案件的有效滤波器的截止频率
then is cut in half from for keywords to kill hurts
然后从关键字杀伤害减少一半
21 kilohertz and then to 500 cycles so let's begin with the forty killer hurt
21千赫兹，然后以500次让我们开始与40杀手的伤害
sampling frequency
采样频率
or ineffective filter cutoff frequency of work killer
或工作杀手无效滤波器的截止频率
now let's reduce net 20 kilohertz am
现在让我们减少净20千赫时
frequency or to kill hurts filter
频率或杀伤害过滤器
and 10 kelleher sampling frequency
和10凯莱赫采样频率
the
该
then finally in my Google Earth family
后来终于在我的谷歌地球的家人
cigars running to me why minor in Psych grueling
跑到我为什么未成年人精极度紧张严罚雪茄
analog all the
模拟所有
I now let's finally include why returning to
我现在让我们终于有为什么回国
a little higher quality ragtime like me the same
高一点的质量拉格泰姆像我一样
theme
主题
right well hopefully
右边还有希望
what you've seen in the demonstration and in this lecture
你所看到的演示和在此讲学
is gives you a sense of feeling
是给你的感觉感
for the analysis and the use
用于分析和使用
I'll discrete-time filters
我将离散时间滤波器
for processing continuous-time signals and
用于处理连续时间信号，并
as you may be aware and as I've tried to indicate
正如你可能知道，正如我一直试图表明
previously in the past this in fact is
以前在过去，这其实是
one very important but not the only but one very important
其中很重要的，但不是唯一的，但其中很重要的
context in which discrete-time filtering
上下文中，离散时间滤波
issues and this in fact is
的问题，这实际上是
an area that is developing rapidly because at the fact dead
这是因为在死亡的事实迅速发展的区域
microprocessors digital technology computers et cetera
微处理器数字技术的计算机等等
afford considerable flexibility
负担相当大的灵活性
in carrying out digital processing of signals
在开展信号数字处理
and it is and went digital processing is used at
它是走了数字处理是用在
naturally corresponds
自然对应
to to implementing the processing
以实施处理
and analyzing it in discrete-time now
现在分析它在离散时间
in the next lecture will be continuing
在下一讲将持续
on another aspect developing another aspect
在另一个方面发展另一个方面
love sampling any particular
爱取样任何特定
what we'll be talking about is sampling of discrete-time signals
我们将谈论的是离散时间信号的采样
as all indicate there one of the contexts in which
因为所有的表示存在于该上下文之一
discrete-time sampling in fact plays an important role
实际上离散时间采样起着重要的作用
is in the context in which
是在上下文中
we are processing continuous-time signals
我们正在处理连续时间信号
using discrete time processing where in fact
使用离散时间处理这里其实
one step that we might want to take in addition to the steps that we've talked
我们可能要考虑除了我们已经讨论过的步骤一步
about here
关于这里
is an additional sampling process following
下面是一个额外的采样过程
whatever kinds of filtering that we that we do well that's a discussion and a
任何类型的过滤，我们认为我们做的很好，这是一个讨论和
topic that will be going into in the next lecture
主题将进入在下一讲
thank you
谢谢